ONYI ANOZIE Houston, TX (832) 293-7743 kamsiri1@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Cloud Architect with over ten (10) years of industry experience in Cloud Engineering, Cloud Product Engineering, and Cloud Architecture. Executed cloud application and cloud architecture with in-depth knowledge in designing, planning, managing, and securing cloud solutions to create a sustainable cloud environment. Acquired a solid grasp over designing, setting up, configuring, and optimizing a cloud computing environment to facilitate accessibility and eliminate cloud design issues for state-of-the-art open-source technologies to a production-ready cloud environment. Developed proficiency in analyzing the process of creating optimal IT solutions on AWS, ensuring AWS cloud best practices, as well as suggested design patterns. Career supported by CompTIA Security+ Certification and Amazon Web Services (AWS) Solutions Architect and Cloud practitioner certification.

- Cloud Engineering
- Project Management
- CloudTrail Monitoring

- Information Security
- Performance Optimization
- System Administration

- Amazon Services
- Customer Service
- Disaster Recovery

EDUCATION | CERTIFICATIONS

Amazon Web Services (AWS) Cloud Practitioner Certification, Amazon Web Services (AWS) Solutions Architect Certification | Security+ | CompTIA Certification.BS in Industrial and Applied Chemistry, IMSU.MS in Healthcare Administration-In Pursuit. Trident University.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Rhema Group Consulting, LLC April 2020-Present DevSecOps Engineer

- Participate in efforts that tailor the company's security policies and standards for use in cloud environments.
- Worked with development team to create a collaborative IT operations model based on Agile and DevOps methodologies and wrote code to support automated IT operations methodology using Java and Python scripting languages.
- Developed reference architectures and proof of concept implementations of cloud security environments
- Managed security risk management and penetration testing of cloud infrastructure, identified and mitigated security risks, and validated security controls
- Develop distributed and redundant cloud infrastructure, focused on the server and storage side of security, constantly embracing new technology and the latest tools
- Led security architecture review, applied security controls, and deployed software applications and infrastructure to meet security standards
- Evaluated operational processes and recommended the best industry and cost-effective solutions.
- Provided support for database upgrades and software deployments.
- Monitored the database performance and developed actionable improvements for any underperformance reports or dashboards.
- Used Python included Boto3 to supplement automation provided by AWS Lambda
- Developed shell scripting and Python programs to automate the data flow on day-to-day tasks.
- Automated the provisioning of environments with Chef and Ansible and deployed environments using Kubernetes containers.
- Structured cluster AutoScaler for Azure Kubernetes service (AKS) by using Terraform and worked with scheduling, deploying and managing pods and replicas in AKS
- Experienced working with Java, OOPs concept and collection framework
- Analyzed the SQL scripts and designed the solution to develop a custom ETL pipeline by using Python
- Supporting customer implementations and ensured success by identifying and applying repeatable best practices.
- Mentoring the team in all technical support, creating and managing infrastructure as a service
- Experience in CI/CD tools such as Azure DevOps, Gitlab, GitHub, Bitbucket, AWS Code Commit,

- and AWS Code Deploy.
- Analyzed requirements and implemented systems to deliver comprehensive system development life cycle solutions.
- Managed cross-functional teams during systems integration projects.
- Produced the strategic plan to ensure solutions aligned with company and industry standards.
- Worked effectively within Agile software development environments to maintain efficient project work, participating in daily scrums, sprints, and retrospectives.
- Ensured all IAM users had multi-factor authentication activation for their individual accounts and also limited the number of IAM users with administrative privileges.
- Worked with end-users to automate and create solutions within the AWS framework that can be managed by direct user groups.
- Encrypted data stored in EBS as an added layer of security.
- Performed security monitoring, security event triage, and incident response
- Hands-on experience building solutions with tools and services such as AWS CloudFormation,
- Terraform, or custom build orchestration tools leveraging SDKs or directly interacting with APIs.
- Designed and implemented monitoring and protection capabilities to help identify and protect against DoS attacks, MITM, EC2 instance compromise, and secret compromise.
- Operational experience with network security appliances with a clear understanding of the architecture behind secure networks, DMZs, NATs, rule placement, VPN setup, and system maintenance.
- Performed root cause analysis, debugging, support, and postmortem analysis for security incidents and service interruptions.
- Working knowledge of software development life cycle (SDLC) and Agile/iterative methodologies.
- Developed POC for docker by Containerizing the web application.
- Designing and implementing system security and data assurance.
- Experience setting up monitoring solutions for infrastructure and services (e.g., ELK, Grafana, Prometheus).
- Experience with frequent and incremental development, testing, and deployment (Blue/Green Deployment).

Zain Management Inc- Houston, TX

January 2017- April 2020

Cloud Security Engineer

- Experience with microservice and container-based application architectures.
- Developed and designed Azure Devops pipeline to manage the resources across multiple subscription in Azure.
- Developed scripts using Java and eclipse IDE on POM pattern under data driven framework and implementing testing using TestNG.
- I developed a Patch Automation using Systems Manager and CloudFormation. The solution Managed over 500 servers.
- Maintained least privileges using IAM and IAC (infrastructure as code) and automated the process using pipelines.
- Educate developers on how to commit their work and how they can make use of automated workflow in CI/CD pipelines.
- Used AWS EBS for deploying and scaling web applications and services developed with Java and Python
- Provided Demo to customers on product (CI/CD pipeline) and its features.
- Developed Java and Python Scripts for AWS Orchestration designing and developing new back-end services, maintaining and expanding our AWS Infrastructure.
- Enabled Cloud Trail across all geographic regions and AWS services to prevent activity monitoring gaps.
- Enabling access logging for Cloud Trail S3 bucket to track access requests and identify potentially unauthorized or unwarranted access attempts
- Assisted with the backup and recovery strategy for applications and databases on cloud platforms.
- Deployed Kubernetes clusters on cloud/on-premises environment with master/minion architecture and wrote many YAML files to create many services like pods, deployments, auto scaling, load balancers, labels, health checks etc.
- Designing and implementing Azure Solutions across range of cloud models like SaaS, PaaS, IaaS, and integrated on premises, On demand workloads with the Azure public cloud.
- Actively participating in building security models, VPC, and Elastic IP for databases on cloud platforms.
- Conducted vulnerability assessments; evaluated business and technical security requirements, prototyping and implementation of applications and technical solutions.
- Drafted, reviewed & amp; maintained architectural diagrams, interface specifications & amp; other architectural

- artifacts as required by the delivery teams and clearly communicated the needs of the solution under development.
- Worked closely with Operations, IT, Support, and Engineering teams to monitor and remediate security incidents.
- Supported product teams in the development of the technical design and documentation.
- Worked with Azure Monitoring tools such as Azure Log Analytics, Azure Network Watcher, and Azure Service health to diagnose and minimize service degradation.
- Automated security tools and processes ensure innovation and strategies that keep pace in the areas of access
- Identified and analyzed system & amp; application-level vulnerabilities and recommended countermeasures/mitigated controls that reduce risk.
- Conducted and facilitated security reviews and threat modeling, including in-depth design reviews throughout the development lifecycle.
- Mentored team members & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects in software development principles, patterns, processes & Dutions Architects & Dutions & Dutions & Dutions & Dutions & Dutions & Dutions
- Responsible for the security of a complex, multi-tenant, fully managed Amazon Web Services (AWS) environment.
- Define and implement perimeter protection for cloud environments, project management, penetration testing, virus scanning, and patching.
- Assisted the company in building a knowledge-based platform to validate its business model and improve the overall security posture.

UAC Emergency Services LLC- Houston TX

Nov 2014- Dec 2016

Systems Administrator-

- Executed the set-up, installation, maintenance, troubleshooting, and upgrade of hardware, software and Peripherals.
- Created and maintained documentation to help train employees to resolve day-to-day issues and knowledge transfer.
- Configured and administered LAN/WAN/MAN communications and network hardware, including routers, switches and firewalls
- Identified and executed process improvements and other enhancements that improve operational efficiency.
- Used network security monitoring tools to identify intrusions and problems in the Network.
- Performed daily backup operations ensuring all required file systems and system data were successfully backed up to the appropriate media, recovery tapes or disks and that the media was recycled and sent off site as necessary.
- Performed daily system monitoring verifying the integrity and availability of all hardware, server resources, load balancing, systems, and key processes reviewing system and application logs, and verifying completion of scheduled jobs such as backups.
- Performed regular file archival and purge, as necessary

United States Navy OCT 2010 – Nov 2014 IT Specialist/HM

- Provided courteous customer service to the facility with over 2500 staff while providing daily technical support. Set up SharePoint site.
- Explained technical information in clear terms to non-technical individuals to promote better understanding.
- Configured new employee profiles for AD with a meticulous sense of attention to detail to meet their specific requirements.
- Successfully communicated and trained all new staff on information security, Network, and Vista access. Isolated workstations with vulnerabilities and resolved issues successfully.
- Created multiple virtual machines using for testing and general use with VMware, installing operating systems ranging from Windows XP to Windows 10 and Linux.
- Used sound judgment to evaluate and troubleshoot technical issues with remote users.
- Knowledgeable in space planning, physical infrastructure, and cable management; worked with Virtual Server setups and LAN configurations.
- Used PowerShell scripts to remotely patch software and install new versions to eliminate security problems and protect data.

Key Skills

• Cloud Security: AWS Security Hub, AWS Guard Duty, AWS Shield, AWS Firewall Manager, AWS Inspector, IAM, Security Groups, NACL, Lacework, Splunk, SignalFx, Nexus, Vault, IPS, and IDS

- Monitoring and Event Management: AWS CloudWatch (Events & Dys.), AWS SNS
- Identity & Decrets Management: AWS Organization, AWS IAM, AWS AD Connector, AWS Workspaces, AWS Secrets Manager
- **AWS Platform**: AWS CloudFormation, AWS Lambda, AWS Systems Manager, S3, VPC, EC2, ELB, RDS, SNS, SQS, Cybersecurity analysis Performance, and scalability optimization
- Governance & Compliance: AWS Config Rules, AWS Organization, AWS Control Tower, AWS Trusted Advisor, AWS Budgets, AWS License Manager
- Cloud Orchestration/Automation: AWS CloudFormation, AWS Lambda, AWS Systems Manager, AWS SSM Parameter Store, Ansible, Docker, Kubernetes
- Network: VPC, VGW, TGW, IGW, NGW, etc. Application Delivery: Jenkins, GitHub, AWS Code Pipeline, AWS Code Commit, Blue/Green deployment, Elastic Beanstalk, microservices, containerization
- Language: Java, SWIFT, React Native, JSON YML, Shell, Python, Nodejs, C#, Visual Studio Code, Spring boot, .NET Core and Visual Basic
- Web: HTML, JavaScript, CSS, React, and Redux
- Database: Snowflake, Teradata, Tableau, Oracle, SQL Server, DB2, and Red Brick
- Engineering: LabVIEW, MATLAB, AutoCAD, Orcaflex, Solidworks, and Civil3D
- Microsoft: Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Project, SharePoint, Microsoft Azure, Access